welcome to MIT course 6 s 0 9 9
欢迎来到麻省理工学院课程 6 s 0 9 9
artificial general intelligence today we
人工智能今天我们
have Ray Kurzweil he is one of the
有Ray Kurzweil他是其中之一
world's leading inventors thinkers and
世界领先的发明家思想家和
futurists with a 30-year track record of
具有30年 历史记录的未来学家
accurate predictions called the Restless
准确的预测称为不安分
genius by The Wall Street Journal and
“华尔街日报” 杂志的天才
the ultimate thinking machine by Forbes
福布斯的终极思维机器
magazine he was selected as one of the
杂志他被选为 其中之一
top entrepreneurs by Inc magazine which
Inc 杂志的顶级企业家
described him as the rightful heir to
形容他是合法的继承人
Thomas Edison PBS selected him as one of
托马斯爱迪生 PBS选择他作为其中之一
the 16 revolutionaries who made America
制造美国的16位革命者
Ray was the principal investigator of
雷 的主要研究者
the first ccd flatbed scanner the first
第一台ccd平板扫描仪
omni font optical character recognition
全向字体 光学字符识别
the first point to speech reading
第一点到语音阅读
machines for the blind the first
盲人机器第一
text-to-speech synthesizer the first
文本到语音合成器第一
music synthesizer capable of creating
音乐合成器 能够创造
the grand piano and other orchestral
大钢琴和其他管弦乐队
instruments and the first commercially
仪器和第一个商业
marketed large vocabulary speech
销售大词汇量的演讲
recognition among his many honors he
在他的众多荣誉中得到认可
received a Grammy Award for outstanding
获得了格莱美奖 优秀
achievements in music technology he's
他是音乐技术的成就
the recipient of the National Medal of
获得国家 勋章
Technology was inducted into the
技术被引入了
National Inventors Hall of Fame holds 21
国家发明家名人堂成立21人
honorary doctorates and honors from
荣誉博士学位和荣誉
three u.s. presidents Ray has written
三位美国总统雷写过
five national best-selling books
五本全国畅销书籍
including the New York Times bestsellers
包括“纽约 时报”畅销书
The Singularity is near from 2005 and
奇点 从2005年开始接近
how to create a mind from 2012 he is
如何从2012年创建的头脑，他是
co-founder and Chancellor of singularity
共同创始人和 奇点 校长
University and a director of engineering
大学和工程总监
at Google heading up a team developing
在谷歌领导 团队发展
machine intelligence and natural
机器智能 和自然
language understanding
语言理解
please give ray a warm welcome
请给雷一个热烈的欢迎
[Applause]
[掌声]
[Music]
[音乐]
it's good to be back I've been in this
回来我很高兴我一直 在这里
lecture hall many times and walked the
演讲厅多次 走了
infinite Carter I came here as an
无限的卡特 我来到这里作为一个
undergraduate in 1965 within a year of
1965年一年 内本科
my being here they started a new major
我在这里他们开了一个新专业
called computer science it did not get
它没有得到 计算机 科学
its own course number that's 6 1 even
它自己的课程编号是6 1 甚至
biotechnology recently got its own
生物技术最近有了自己的
course number but how many of you are CS
课程编号，但你们中有多少人是CS
majors ok how many of you do work in
主修好你们有多少 人 在做什么工作
deep learning how many of you have heard
深入了解你们有多少人听过
of deep learning here I came here first
在这里深入学习我先来到这里
in 1952 when I was 14 I became excited
1952年我14岁的时候，我很兴奋
about artificial intelligence it had
关于人工智能它有
only gotten its name six years earlier
只有得到它的名字 六年前
the 1956 Dartmouth conference by Marvin
1956年由马文举行的达特茅斯会议
Minsky and John McCarthy so I wrote
明斯基和约翰麦卡锡所以我写道
Minsky a letter there was no email back
明斯基的一封信也没有回复电子邮件
then and he invited me up he spent all
然后，他邀请我 ，他花了所有
day with me as if he had nothing else to
和我在一起的日子好像他什么都没有
do he was a consummate educator
他是 一个完美的教育家 吗？
I then and the AI field had already
那时我 和AI领域已经存在了
bifurcated into two warring camps the
分为两个交战营地
symbolic school which Minsk II was
明斯克二世的象征性学校
associated with and the connectionist
与联系主义者联系在一起
school was not widely known in fact I
学校其实 并不广为人知
think it's still not widely known that
认为它仍然不为人所知
Minsk II actually invented the neural
明斯克 II 实际上发明了神经
net in 1953 but he had become negative
1953年净，但他变得消极
about it largely because there was a lot
关于它主要是因为有很多
of hype that these giant branes could
这些巨型肌肉可以宣传的炒作
solve any problem
解决任何问题
so the first popular neural nets the
所以第一个流行的神经网络
perceptron was being promulgated by
感知正被颁布
Frank Rosenblatt at Cornell so Minsky
康奈尔的弗兰克罗森布拉特所以明斯基
set out what are you going now and
列出你 现在 要做什么
saying I said to see Rosenblatt at core
我说要看罗森布拉特 的核心
now is that don't bother doing that and
现在是，也懒得这样做， 并
I went there and Rosenblatt was touting
我去了那里，罗森布拉特正在兜售
the perceptron that it ultimately would
它最终会产生的感知器
be able to solve any problem so I
能够 解决任何问题，所以我
brought some printed letters that had
带来了一些打印的字母
the camera and it did a perfect job of
相机和它做了一个完美的工作
recognizing them as long as they were
只要 他们认识到他们就会认出来
courier ten different types I didn't
快递 十种不同类型 我没有
work at all and he said but don't worry
工作，他说，但 不要 担心
we can take the output of the perceptron
我们可以拿出 感知器 的 输出
or feed it as the input to another
或者将其作为 另一个 的 输入
perceptron and take the output of that
感知并利用 该 输出
and feed it to a third layer and as we
然后把它喂给第三层，就像我们一样
add more layers it'll get smarter and
添加更多图层，它会变得更聪明
smarter and generalize and so that's
更智能和概括，所以那就是
interesting if you even tried that well
有趣的是，你甚至尝试过这么好
no but it's high on our research agenda
不，但它在 我们的研究议程中占据重要位置
things did not move quite as quickly
事情并没有那么快
back then as they do now he died nine
那时他们现在已经九岁了
years later never having tried that idea
几年后 从未尝试过这个想法
turns out to be remarkably prescient I
事实证明我是非常有先见之明的
mean he never tried multi-layer neural
意味着他从未尝试过多层神经
nets and all the excitement we see now
网 和我们现在看到的所有兴奋
about deep learning comes from a
关于深学习来自于
combination of two things
两件事的结合
both many layer neural Nets and the law
许多层神经网络和法律
of accelerating returns which I'll get
加速回报，我会得到
to a little bit later which is basically
到了一点点 ，这基本上是
the exponential growth of computing so
计算的指数增长 如此
that we can run these massive nets and
我们可以运行这些庞大的 网络和
handle massive amounts of data it would
处理大量数据
be decades before that idea was tried
几十年前，这个想法被尝试了
several decades later three level neural
几十年后三级神经
nets were tried there were a little bit
网上试过了一 点点
better they could deal with multiple
他们可以更好地处理 多重问题
type styles still weren't very flexible
类型样式 仍然不是很灵活
that's not hard to add other layers it's
这并不难添加其他图层
a very straightforward concept there was
有一个非常简单的概念
a math problem the disappearing gradient
数学问题消失的梯度
or the exploding gradient which I'm sure
或者我确定的爆炸梯度
many of you are familiar with basically
很多人基本都熟悉
you need to take maximum advantage of
你需要 采取 的 最大的优势
the range of values in the gradients and
渐变和值的范围
not let them explode or disappear and
不要让它们爆炸或消失
lose the resolution that's a fairly
失去的是 一个相当分辨率
straightforward mathematical
直截了当的数学
transformation with that insight we
与 洞察力转变我们
could now go 200 layer neural nets and
现在可以去200层神经网络了
that's behind sort of all the fantastic
这是所有梦幻般的背后
gains that we've seen recently
我们最近看到收益
alphago trained on every online game and
alphago 训练每个 在线游戏和
then became a fair go player it then
然后成为一个公平的棋手它，然后
trained itself by playing itself and
通过自我锻炼来训练自己
soared past the best human alphago zero
飙升过最好的人类alphago 零
started with no human input at all
一开始没有任何人为输入
within hours of iteration sort Pascal
迭代后几小时内排序 Pascal
phago also soared past the best just
phago也 飙升过最好的 公正
programs they had another innovation
他们有另一项创新的计划
basically you need to evaluate the
基本上你 需要评估
quality of the board at each point they
他们每个点的董事会质量
used another hundred layer neural nets
使用了另外一百层神经网络
to do that evaluation so there's still a
做那个 评估， 所以还有一个
problem in the field which is there's a
这个领域存在问题
motto that life begins at a billion
生活开始于 十亿的座右铭
examples
例子
one of the reasons I'm at Google is we
我在谷歌的原因之一就是我们
have a billion examples for examples of
以十亿个例子为例
pictures of dogs and cats that are
狗和猫的图片是
labeled so you got a picture of a cat
标记为你 有一张猫的照片
and it says cat and then you can learn
它说 猫然后你可以学习
from it and you need a lot of them
从它，你需要很多
alphago trained on a million online
alphago在线上训练了一百万
moves that's how many we had of master
移动 那就是 我们掌握了多少
games and that only created a sort of
游戏，只创造了一种
fair go player a good amateur could
公平的球员一个好的业余球员可以
defeated so they worked around that in
击败，使他们在工作围绕
the case of go by basically generating
通过基本生成的情况
an infinite amount of data by having the
通过拥有无限量的数据
system play itself had a chat with
系统玩本身聊天
Denver's house office you know what kind
丹佛的家庭办公室，你知道什么样的
of situations can you do that with you
情况你能和你一起做吗
have to have some way of simulating the
必须有一些 模拟 的方法
world so go or chess are even though go
世界如此去或国际象棋即使去
is considered a difficult game it's
被认为是一场艰难的比赛
a-you know the definition of it can
你知道 它 的 定义 吗？
exist on one page so you can simulate it
存在于 一个页面上，因此您可以模拟 它
that applies to math I mean amass axioms
这适用于数学 我的意思是 积累公理
are can be contained on a page or two
都可以 包含一两页上
it's not very complicated it gets more
它变得越来越复杂并不是很 复杂
difficult when you have real-life
当你有现实生活时 很难
situations like biology so we have
像 生物学 这样的情况我们有
biological simulators but the simulators
生物模拟器，但模拟器
on perfect so learning from the
完美所以从中 学习
simulators will only be as good as the
模拟器只会像
simulators that's actually the key to
模拟器实际上是关键
being able to do deep learning on
能够做深度学习上
biology
生物学
autonomous vehicles you need real-life
自动驾驶汽车，你需要现实生活
data so the way mo systems have gone
数据所以 mo系统已经 消失了
three and a half million miles
三百五十万英里
that's good that's enough data to then
那个数据足够好了
create a very good simulator so the
创建一个非常好的模拟器所以
simulator is really quite realistic
模拟器真的很 现实
because they had a lot of real-world
因为他们有很多 现实世界
experience and the they've got a billion
经验，他们有十亿
miles in the simulator but we don't
模拟器中的里程数，但我们没有
always have that opportunity to either
总是有这样的 机会 要么
create the data or have the data around
创建数据或拥有数据
humans can learn from a small number of
人类可以从少数人中学习
examples your significant other your
你的重要人物的例子
professor your boss your investor can
教授你的老板你的投资者可以
tell you something once or twice and you
和 你说一两次
might actually learn from that some
可能实际上可以从中学到一些
humans have been reported to do that
据报道人类会这样做
and that's kind of the remaining
那是剩下的
advantage of humans now there's actually
现在实际上是人类的优势
no back propagation in the human brain
在人脑中 没有反向传播
it doesn't use deep learning it uses a
它不使用深度学习它使用
different architecture that same year in
同年的不同建筑
1962 I wrote a paper how I thought the
1962年我写了一篇论文，我是怎么想的
human brain worked there was actually
人脑实际上在那里工作
very little neuroscience to go on there
很少的神经 去那里
was one neuroscientist Vernon mount
是一位神经科学家弗农山
Castle that had something relevant to
有与之相关的城堡
say which as he did I mean there was a
说他做了什么我的意思是有 一个
the common wisdom at the time and
当时的共同智慧和
there's still a lot of neuroscience that
还有很多神经科学
says say this that we have all these
说这说我们有这些
different regions of the brain they do
他们做 的 大脑的不同区域
different things they must be different
他们必须有所不同
there's v1 in the back of the head where
在头后部 有 v1
the optic nerve spills into that can
视神经溢出到那个可以
tell that that's a curved line that
告诉这是一个曲线是
that's a straight line does these simple
这是一条简单的直线
feature extractions on visual images
可视图像上的特征提取
it's actually a large part of the
它实际上是很大一部分
neocortex does the fusiform gyrus up
新皮质做了梭形回
here which can recognize faces we know
这里可以识别我们知道的 面孔
that because if it gets knocked out
因为如果它被 淘汰了
through injury or stroke people can't
通过伤或中风的人不能
recognize faces they will learn it again
认识面孔， 他们将 再次 学习它
with a different region of the neocortex
与新皮层的不同区域
is the famous frontal cortex which does
是着名的额叶皮层
language in poetry and music so these
诗歌和音乐中的 语言 就是这些
must work on different principles he did
必须遵循他所做的不同原则
autopsies on the neocortex and all these
对新皮质和所有这些进行尸体解剖
different regions and found they all
不同的地区，发现他们都
looked the same they had the same
看起来 和他们一样
repeating pattern same interconnections
重复模式相同的互连
he said neocortex is neocortex so I had
他说新皮质是新皮质，所以我有
that hint otherwise I can actually
那一抹否则我 其实 可以
observe human brains in action which I
观察人类的大脑在行动，我
did from time to time and there's a lot
不时做， 而且有很多
of hints that you can get that way for
提示 你可以通过这种方式获得
example if I ask you to recite the
例如，如果我请你背诵
alphabet you actually don't do it from A
字母你 实际上不是从A做的
to Z you do it as a sequence of
到Z 你做的是一系列的
sequences ABCD efg hijk so we learn
序列ABCD efg hijk 所以我们学习
things that secret forward sequences of
秘密前进序列的东西
sequences forward because if I ask you
序列向前，因为如果我问你
to recite the alphabet backwards you
向后背诵你的字母表
can't do it unless you learn that as a
除非你 了解到 这一点，否则不能这样做
new sequence so these are all
新序列所以这些都是
interesting hints I wrote a paper that I
有趣的提示我写了一篇论文 ，我
that the neocortex is organized as a
大脑皮层被组织成一个
hierarchy of modules in each module can
在 每个模块 中的模块的层次结构可以
learn a simple pattern and that's how I
学习一个简单的模式，这就是 我
got to meet President Johnson and that
得到了满足 约翰逊总统和
initiated a half-century of thinking
发起 了半个世纪的思考
about this issue I came to MIT to study
关于这个问题 我来麻省理工学院学习
with Marvin Minsky actually came for two
与马文明斯基实际上来了两个
reasons one the Minsky became my mentor
明斯基成为我的导师的原因
which was a mentorship that lasted for
这是一个持续的指导
over 50 years the fact that MIT was so
超过50年，麻省理工学院就是如此
advanced it actually had a computer
先进它实际上有一台电脑
which the other colleges I considered
我考虑过的其他大学
didn't have it was an IBM 7090 for 32 K
没有它是 32 K 的IBM 7090
of 36 bit words so it's 150 K of course
36位字，所以它当然是150 K.
storage to microsecond cycle time two
存储到微秒循环时间 二
cycles for instructions or a quarter of
指令周期或四分之一
a myth and that thousands of students
一个神话和成千上万的学生
and professors shared that one machine
和 教授分享了这台机器
in 2012 I wrote a book about this thesis
在2012年，我写了一本关于这篇论文的书
is now actually an explosion of
现在实际上是爆炸性的
neuroscience evidence to support it the
神经科学证据支持它
European brain reverse engineering
欧洲脑逆向工程
project has identified a repeating
项目已经确定了重复
module about a hundred neurons it's
模块大约有一百个神经元
repeated three hundred million times
重复三亿次
it's about 30 billion neurons in the
它 在 约 30十亿的神经元
neocortex the neocortex is the outer
新皮质是新皮质的外层
layer of the brain that's part where we
大脑的 一层，是 我们的一部分
do our thinking and they can see in each
做我们的思考，他们可以看到每一个
module axons coming in from another
模块轴突从另一个进来
module and then the output acts the
模块，然后输出作用
single output accent of that
单输出重音
Jil goes as the input to another module
Jil 作为 另一个模块 的输入
so we can see it organized as a
所以我们 可以看到它组织成一个
hierarchy it's not a physical hierarchy
层次结构它不是物理 层次结构
it's the hierarchy comes from these
这是层次结构来自这些
connections the neocortex is a very thin
连接新皮质 非常薄
structure it's actually one module thick
结构它实际上是一个模块厚
there's six layers of neurons but it
有六层神经元，但它
constitutes one module and we can see
构成一个模块，我们可以看到
that it learns in simple pattern and
它以简单的模式学习
various reasons I cite in the book the
种种原因我举 书中的
pattern recognition model that's using
正在使用的模式识别模型
is basically a hidden Markov model how
基本上是一个隐马尔可夫模型如何
many of you have worked with Markov
很多人都和马尔科夫一起工作过
models okay
模特没关系
that's usually no hands go open I asked
我 问道 ， 通常没有人会 打开 手
that question but Markov model is not it
那个问题，但Markov模型不是它
is learned but it's not back propagation
已经学会 但它不会 反向传播
it can learn local features so it's very
它可以学习本地功能，所以它 非常适合
good for speech recognition and the
有利于语音识别 和
speech recognition network I did in the
我做过的语音识别网络
80s used these Markov models that became
80年代使用了这些马尔可夫模型
the standard approach because it can
标准方法，因为它可以
deal with local variations so the fact
处理当地的变化 所以事实
that a vowel is stretched you can learn
一个元音被拉伸你 可以学习
that in a Markov model it doesn't learn
在马尔可夫模型中它没有学习
long distance relationships that's
异地恋这
handled by the hierarchy and something
由层次结构和 某事处理
we don't fully understand yet is exactly
我们还没有完全理解
how the neocortex creates that hierarchy
新皮层如何创建该层次结构
but we have figured out how it can
但我们已经弄清楚它是如何 做到的
connect this module to this module does
连接这个模块这个模块 会
it then grow I mean there's no virtual
它然后增长我的意思是没有虚拟
communication or wireless communication
通信或无线通信
it's actually connection so does it grow
它实际上是连接所以 它会增长
an axon you know from one place to
你从一个地方知道的轴突
another which could be inches apart
另一个可能相隔几英寸
actually they all all these connections
实际上他们所有这些联系
are there from birth like the streets
是否 有来自像街上诞生
and avenues of Manhattan there's
和那里的曼哈顿大道
vertical and horizontal connections so
垂直和水平的连接，以便
if the it decides and how it makes that
如果它决定它是如何做到的
decision it's still not fully understood
决定还没有完全理解
that it wants to connect this module to
它想要将此模块连接 到
this module there's already a vertical
这个模块已经有了一个纵向
horizontal and a vertical connection it
水平和垂直连接
just activates them we can actually see
只是激活他们我们实际上可以看到
that now and I can see that happening in
现在，我可以看到发生的事情
real time on non-invasive brain scans
实时 进行非侵入性脑部扫描
so there's a current amount of evidence
所以有证据 电流量
that's in fact the neocortex is a
事实上， 新皮质是一个
hierarchy of modules that can learn each
模块的层次结构能互相学习
module learns a simple sequential
模块学习一个简单的顺序
pattern and even though the patterns we
模式 ，即使我们的模式
perceived don't seem like sequences they
感觉 似乎不像他们的序列
may seem three-dimensional or even more
可能看起来是三维甚至更多
complicated they are in fact represented
事实上他们很复杂
as sequences but the complexity comes in
作为序列， 但复杂性来自
with the hierarchy so the neocortex
与层次结构， 所以neocortex
emerged 200 million years ago with
2亿年前出现 了
mammals all mammals have a neocortex
哺乳动物所有哺乳动物都有新皮质
it's one of the distinguishing features
这是一个与众不同的特色
of mammals these first mammals were
哺乳动物的 这些第一哺乳动物是
small they were rodents but they were
小的他们是啮齿动物， 但他们是
capable a new type of thinking other
能够在 新的 思维 类型 等 的
non-mammalian animals had fixed
非哺乳动物已经固定
behaviors but those fixed behaviors were
行为，但那些固定的行为是
very well adapted for their ecological
非常适应 他们的生态
niche but these new mammals could invent
利基但这些新的哺乳动物可能会发明
a new behavior so creativity and
一种新的行为， 所以创造力 和
innovation was one feature of the
创新是的一个特征
neocortex so a mouse is escaping a
neocortex 所以老鼠逃脱了
predator its usual escape path is
捕食者通常的逃生路径是
blocked it will invent a new behavior to
堵住它会创造一个新的行为
deal with it probably wouldn't work but
处理它可能不会起作用
if it did work it would remember it and
如果它确实有效，它会记住它
would have a new behavior and that
会有新的行为
behavior could spread virally through
行为可以通过病毒传播
the community another Mouse watching
社区另一只老鼠在看
this was with say to itself that was
这就是对自己的说法
really clever going around that rock I'm
真正聪明的岩石 ，我 周围发生
gonna remember to do that and it would
要记得 这样做， 它会
have a new behavior didn't help these
有一个新的行为没有帮助这些
early mammals that much because as I say
早期的哺乳动物，因为正如我所说
the non-mammalian animals were very well
非哺乳动物非常好
adapted to their niches and nothing much
适应 他们的 利基，没有什么
happened for a hundred and thirty five
发生了一百 三十五
million years but then 65 million years
百万年，但随后6500 万年
ago something did happened there was a
以前确实发生了一件事
sudden violent change to the environment
突然暴力改变 环境
we now call it the Cretaceous extinction
我们现在称之为白垩纪灭绝
event there's been debate as to whether
事件是否有争论
it was a media or an asteroid I mean a
它是媒体或小行星，我的意思是
meteor or a volcanic eruption the
流星或火山爆发 了
asteroid or meteor hypothesis is in the
小行星或流星假说在
ascendancy but if you dig down to an
优势， 但如果你挖到一个
area of rock reflecting 65 million years
岩石面积反映了6500万年
ago the
以前的
geologists will explain that it shows a
地质学家将解释它显示了一个
very violent sudden change to the
非常暴力的突然变化
environment we see it all around the
环境我们 在周围 看到 它
globe so is a worldwide phenomenon the
截止所以 是一个世界性的现象
reason we call it an extinction event is
我们称它为灭绝事件的原因是
that's when the dinosaurs went extinct
那是恐龙灭绝的时候
that's when 75% of all the animal and
那是所有 动物和动物的 75％
plant species went extinct and that's
植物物种灭绝了
when mammals overtook their ecological
当哺乳动物超过其生态
niche so to anthropomorphize biological
利基因此拟人化生物
evolution said to itself this neocortex
进化说自己这个新皮层
is pretty good stuff and it began to
它是非常 好的东西，它开始 了
grow it so-now mammals got bigger their
如此 - 现在哺乳动物变得更大了
brains got bigger at an even faster pace
大脑以更快的速度变大
taking up a larger fraction of their
占据了他们的大部分
body the neocortex got bigger even
身体新皮质甚至变大了
faster than that and developed these
比 这 更快 ，并开发这些
curvatures that are distinctive of a
曲率是一个独特的
primate brain basically to increase its
灵长类大脑基本上要 增加它
surface area but if you stretched it out
表面积， 但如果你伸展它
the human neocortex is still a flat
人体新皮质仍然是扁平的
structure it's about the size of a table
结构它是关于 表 的大小
napkin just as thin and it's basically
餐巾一样薄，基本上就是这样
created primates which became dominance
创造了成为 支配地位的 灵长类动物
in their ecological niche then something
在他们的生态位中然后是某种东西
else happened two million years ago
其他事发生在两百万年前
biological evolution decided to increase
生物进化 决定增加
the neocortex further and increase the
新皮质进一步增加
size of the enclosure and basically
外壳的大小和基本上
filled up the frontal cortex with our
用我们的方法填满了额叶皮层
big skulls with more neocortex and up
有更多新皮质和更多的大头骨
until recently it was felt that as I
直到最近才 感觉到像我一样
said that this was the frontal cortex
说这 是 额叶皮层
was different because it does these
是不同的，因为它做到了这些
qualitatively different things but we
质量上不同的东西，但我们
now realize that it's really just
现在意识到这 真的很 公正
additional neocortex so remember what we
额外的新皮质所以记住我们
did with it we're already doing a very
做到了 我们已经做了很多
good job of being primates so we put it
好好做 灵长类动物，所以我们把它
at the top of the neocortical hierarchy
在新皮质层次结构的顶部
and we increased the size of the
我们增加了它的大小
hierarchy it was maybe 20% more
层次结构 是可能 增加 20％
neocortex but it doubled it tripled the
新皮质， 但它翻了三倍
number of levels because as you go up
你上去时 的等级数量
the hierarchy it's kind of like a
层次结构有点像
pyramid there's fewer and fewer modules
金字塔的 模块 越来越 少
and that was the enabling factor for us
这对 我们来说是一个有利因素
to invent language and art music every
去 创造语言 和艺术音乐表演
human culture we've ever discovered has
我们曾经发现了人类文化有
music no primary culture really has
音乐没有原始文化真的有
music there's debate about that but it's
音乐有关于那个的辩论， 但它是
really true
真的
invention technology technology required
需要发明技术技术
another evolutionary adaptation which is
另一种进化适应
this humble appendage here no other
这个卑微的附属物在这里别无他物
animal has that if you look at a chimp
动物有，如果你看一只黑猩猩
and see it looks like they have a
看看它看起来像 他们有一个
similar hand but the thumb is actually
类似的手，但拇指实际上
down here doesn't work very well if you
到 这里 并没有 很好地工作，如果你
watch them trying to grab a stick so we
看着他们试图抓住一根棍子， 所以我们
could imagine creative solutions yeah I
可以想象创造性的解决方案是的我
could take that branch and strip off the
可以把那个 分支 剥离掉
leaves and put a point on it and we
离开并指出它和我们
could actually carry out these ideas and
实际上可以实现这些想法和
create tools and then use tools to
创建工具，然后使用工具
create new tools and it started a whole
创建新 工具， 它开始了一个整体
nother evolutionary process of
其他进化过程
tool-making and that all came with the
工具制造，所有这一切都伴随 着
with the neocortex
与新皮质
so Larry Page read my book in 2012 and
所以拉里佩奇在2012年读了我的书
liked it so I met with him in Essen for
喜欢它所以我在埃森遇到了他
an investment in a company I'd started
对我开始的公司的投资
actually a couple weeks earlier to
实际上几个 星期前
develop those ideas commercially because
商业上 发展这些 想法是因为
that's how I went about things as a
这就是我去的事情 作为
serial entrepreneur
连续创业者
and said well we'll invest but let me
并说我们会投资，但让我
give you a better idea what you do it
让你更好地了解你做了什么
here at Google we have a billion
在Google，我们有十亿美元
pictures of dogs and cats and we've got
狗和猫的图片， 我们有
a lot of other data and lots of
很多其他数据和很多
computers and lots of talent all of
电脑和很多人才
which is true and says well I don't know
这是真的 ，说得好，我不知道
I just started this company to develop
我刚刚开始这家公司的发展
this is well by your company and how you
你的公司以及 你如何 做得很好
got a value a company that hasn't done
得到了一个没有 做过的公司的价值
anything just started a couple weeks ago
东西刚开始几个 星期前
and he said we can value anything so I
他说我们可以做任何重要的事情
took my first job five years ago and
五年前我的第一份工作
I've been basically applying this model
我基本上已经应用了这个模型
this hierarchical model to understanding
这个层次模型 来理解
language which i think really is the
语言，我觉得真的 是
holy grail of AI I think Turing was
人工智能的圣杯我认为图灵是
correct in designating basically text
在指定基本文本时是正确的
communication as what we now call a
我们现在称之为沟通
turing-complete problem that requires
图灵完整的问题需要
there's no simple NLP tricks it you can
你可以没有简单的NLP技巧
apply to pass a valid Turing test with
适用于通过有效的图灵测试 用
an emphasis on the word valid mitch
强调 有效的 mitch 这个词
kapor and i had a six month debate on
kapor和我进行了六个月的辩论
what the rules should be because if you
规则应该 是什么， 因为如果你
read Turing's 1950 paper he describes
阅读他描述的 图灵1950年的论文
this in a few paragraphs and doesn't
这 在几个段落中没有
really describe how to go about it but
真的描述了如何 去做 但是
if it's a valid Turing test meaning it's
如果这是一个有效的图灵测试意味着它
really convincing you through an
真的说服你通过
interrogation and dialogue that it's a
审讯和对话，这是一个
human that requires a full range of
人类需要 全方位的
human intelligence and I think that test
人类的智慧 和我认为的考验
has to the test of time we're making
必须考验我们正在制作的时间
very good progress on that I mean just
对 ，我的意思 只是 很好的进展
last week you may have read that two
上周你 可能已经读过那两个了
systems
系统
asked paragraph comprehension test it's
要求段落理解测试它
really very impressive winning came to
非常令人印象深刻的胜利来了
Google we were trying to past these
谷歌， 我们试图 通过这些
paragraph comprehension tests we aced
段落理解测试我们很快
the first the first grade test second
第一级考试 第二名
grade tests were kind of got average
等级测试有点平均
performance and the third grade test had
表现和三年级考试有
too much inference already you had to
你必须做太多的推论
know some common-sense knowledge as it's
知道一些常识性的 知识
called and make implications of things
叫做并对 事物产生影响
that were in different parts of the
那是在不同的部分
paragraph and there's too much inference
段落，有太多的推论
and it really didn't didn't work so this
它真的没有没有工作 ，所以这
is now adult level it's just slightly
现在是成人水平， 它只是 略微
surpassed average human performance but
超过了人类的平均表现但是
we've seen that once something an AI
我们已经看到曾经的人工智能
does something it average human levels
做一些平均人的水平
it doesn't take long for it to soar past
它不会花很长时间 才能过去
average human levels I think it'll take
平均人的水平，我认为它需要
longer in language and it did in some
语言更长，而且有些语言也有
simple games like go but it's actually
像go这样的 简单游戏， 但事实上
very impressive that it surpasses now
非常令人印象深刻的是它 现在 超越 了
average human performance used at LST M
LST M使用的人均表现
long short temporal memory but if you
长短的时间记忆， 但如果你
look at the adult test in order to
看成人的测试， 以
answer these questions it has to put
回答 它必须提出的 这些 问题
together inferences and implications of
共同的推论和影响
several different things in the
几个不同的东西
paragraph with some common sense
有一些 常识的段落
knowledge is not explicitly stated so
知识没有明确说明
that's I think a pretty impressive
那我觉得非常令人印象深刻
milestone so I I've been developing I've
里程碑所以我一直在发展 我
got a team of about 45 people and we've
有一个团队约45人， 我们已经
been developing this hierarchical model
一直在开发这种分层模型
we don't use Markov models because we
我们不使用马尔可夫模型
can use deep learning for each module
可以为每个模块使用深度学习
and so we create an embedding for each
所以我们为每个人创建一个嵌入
word and we create an embedding for each
单词，我们为每个人创建一个嵌入
sentence this is we have a I can talk
这句话我们有一个 我可以说话
about it because we have a published
关于它，因为 我们已经发表了
paper on it it can take into
它可以采取的纸张
consideration context
考虑因素
if you use smart reply on G confused
如果你使用智能回复G 困惑
email on your phone you'll see it gives
你会看到 手机 上的电子邮件
you three suggestions for responses
你有三个回应的建议
that's called Smart reply there are
这就是所谓的智能 回复 有
simple suggestions but it has to
简单的建议，但它必须
actually understand perhaps a
实际上 也许 了解 一个
complicated email and the quality of the
复杂的电子邮件和质量
suggestions is really quite good quite
建议真的很不错
on point that's for my team using this
对于我的团队使用这个点
kind of hierarchical model so instead of
一种 层次模型 ，而不是
Markov models that uses embeddings
使用嵌入的马尔可夫模型
because we can use back propagation we
因为我们可以使用反向传播
might as well use it but I think what's
不妨用它， 但我 想是什么
missing from deep learning is this
缺乏深度学习是这个
hierarchical aspect of understanding
理解的等级方面
because the world is hierarchical that's
因为世界是等级的
why evolution developed a hierarchical
为什么进化发展了等级
brain structure to understand the
了解大脑结构
natural hierarchy in the world
世界自然的等级制度
and there are several problems with big
大有几个问题
deep neural nets one is the fact that
深层神经网一是事实
you really do need a billion examples
你确实需要十亿个例子
and we don't sometimes we can generate
我们有时不能生成
them it's in the case of NGO or if we
他们这是在 非政府组织 的情况下 ，或者如果我们
have a really good simulator as in the
有一个非常好的模拟器，如
case of autonomous vehicles not quite
自动 驾驶汽车的情况 并不完全
the case yet in biology very often you
但在生物学中的情况下， 很多 时候你
don't have a billion example if you
如果你没有十亿个例子
suddenly have billions of examples of
突然有数十亿的例子
language but they're not annotated and
语言， 但他们 没有注释和
how would you annotate it anyway with
你怎么用它来注释 呢？
more language that we can't understand
更多我们无法理解的语言
in the first place so that's kind of a
首先，这是 一种
chicken and an egg problem so I believe
鸡和鸡蛋 问题 所以我相信
this hierarchical structures needed
需要这种等级结构
another criticism of deep neural Nets
对深层神经 网络的 另一种批评
they don't explain themselves very well
他们没有很好地解释自己
it's a big black box that gives you
这是一个给你的大黑盒子
pretty remarkable answers I mean in the
我的意思是非常出色的答案
case of these games demos described it's
这些游戏 演示的情况 描述了它
playing in both go and chess is almost
在国际象棋和国际象棋比赛中几乎都是
an alien intelligence because we do
外星人的情报因为我们这样做
things that were shocking to you and
让你 和 你感到震惊的事情
experts like sacrificing a queen and a
专家喜欢牺牲女王和女王
bishop at the same time or in close
主教在同一时间或 近在咫尺
succession which shocked everybody but
连续震惊了所有人但是
then went on to win or early in a go
然后去赢得或在去年初
game putting a piece at the corner of
比赛把一块放在角落 里
the board which is kind of crazy to most
董事会对大多数人来说都是疯狂的
experts because you really want to start
专家，因为你真的想要开始
controlling territory and yet it on
控制领土，然而它
reflection that was the brilliant move
反思是一个辉煌的举动
that enabled it to win that game but it
这让它赢得了那 场比赛 但是它
doesn't really explain how it does these
并没有真正解释 它是 如何 做到的
things so if yeah if you have a
所以，如果是的话，如果 你有一个
hierarchy it's much better at explaining
层次结构 在解释方面 要 好得多
it because you could look at the content
因为你可以查看内容
of the of the modules in the hierarchy
层次结构 中的模块
and they'll explain what they're doing
他们会解释 他们在做什么
and just and on the first application of
而且只是在 第一次申请 时
applying this to health and medicine
将此应用于健康和医学
this will get into high gear and we're
这将进入高速档，我们就是
going to really see us break out at the
真正看到我们突然 爆发了
linear extension to longevity that we've
我们的 长寿线性延伸
experienced I believe we're only about a
经验丰富我相信我们 只是一个
decade away from longevity escape
十年远离长寿逃生
velocity we're adding more time than is
速度我们增加的时间比
going by not just the infant life
不只是婴儿生活
expectancy but to your remaining life
期待，但你的余生
expectancy I think if someone is
期待我认为如果有人
diligent they can be there already I
勤奋他们可以在那里我
think I've
我想我
at longevity escape velocity now a word
在长寿逃生速度现在一句话
on what life expectancy means it used to
关于预期寿命的含义
be assumed that not much would happen so
假设不会 发生 太多 事情
whatever your life expectancy is with or
无论你的 预期寿命 如何
without scientific progress it really
它真的没有科学进步
didn't matter now it matters a lot so
现在没有问题它 的问题很多 ，所以
life expectancy really means you know
预期寿命真的意味着你知道
how long would you live what's the in
你会活多久什么是在
terms of a statistical likelihood if
统计上的可能性，如果条款
there were not continued scientific
没有持续的科学
progress but that's a very inaccurate
进步， 但这是 非常不准确的
assumption that scientific progress
假设科学进步
is extremely rapid I mean just as an AI
非常快我的意思就像AI一样
in biotech there are advances now every
在生物技术领域，每一项都有进步
week is quite stunning
一周相当惊人
now you can have a computed life
现在你可以拥有计算生命
expectancies let's say 30 years 50 years
预期让我们说30 年 50年
70 years from now you can still be hit
70年后你仍然可以被击中
by the proverbial bus tomorrow we're
我们明天将通过众所周知的公共汽车
working on that with self-driving
通过自驾车开展工作
vehicles but we'll get we'll get to a
车辆， 但我们会得到一个
point I think if you're diligent you can
点 我觉得 如果你勤奋，你可以
be there now in terms of basically
现在基本上是在那里
advancing your own statistical life
推进自己的统计生活
expectancy
期待
at least to keep pace with the passage
至少跟上通道的步伐
of time I think it would be there for
时间 我 认为它会在那里
most of the population at least if
大多数人口 至少 如果
they're diligent within about a decade
他们在大约十年内勤奋
so if we can hang in there we may get to
所以，如果我们能够坚持到那里，我们可能会 去
see the remarkable century ahead thank
看到前面 这个非凡的世纪 谢谢
you very much no question please raise
你非常感谢请提出
your hand we'll get your mic hi
你的手我们会得到你的麦克风
so you mentioned both neural neural
所以你提到神经神经
network models and symbolic models and I
网络模型和符号模型和我
was wondering how far have you been
想知道多远 你去过
thinking about combining these two
考虑将这两者结合起来
approaches creating a symbiosis between
在两者之间创造共生的方法
neural models and symbolic ones I don't
神经模型和象征性的我不这样做
think we want to use symbolic models as
我们认为我们想用符号模型作为
they've been used how many are familiar
他们已经习惯了多少人都 熟悉了
with the psych project
与心理项目
that was a very diligent effort in Texas
这是在德克萨斯州非常勤奋的努力
to define all of common-sense reasoning
定义所有常识推理
and it kind of collapsed on itself and
它有点崩溃了
became impossible to debug because you
因为 你而 无法调试
fix one thing and it break three other
解决一件事，它 打破另外三 件事
things that complexity ceiling has
复杂性天花板有的东西
become typical of of trying to define
成为典型的试图定义
things through logical rules now it does
现在 通过逻辑规则 做的事情
seem that humans can understand logical
似乎 人类可以理解逻辑
rules we have logical rules written down
规则我们写下了逻辑规则
for things like law and game playing and
用于法律和游戏 等方面
so on but you can actually define a
等等你可以实际定义一个
connectionist system to have such a high
连接系统有这么高的
reliability on a certain type of action
某种行为的可靠性
that it looks like it's a symbolic rule
它看起来 像是一个象征性的 规则
even though it's represented in a
即使它代表了一个
connectionist way and connection systems
连接方式和连接 系统
can both capture the soft edges because
可以捕获软边缘，因为
many things in life are not sharply
生活中的许多事情并不严重
defined they can also generate
定义他们也可以生成
exceptions so you you don't want to
例外， 所以你不想
sacrifice your queen in chess accept
在国际象棋中牺牲你的女王 接受
certain situations that might be a good
某些可能是好的情况
idea so you can capture that kind of
想法， 所以 你可以抓住那种
complexity so we do want to be able to
复杂性， 所以我们希望 能够
learn from accumulated human wisdom that
从 积累的人类智慧中学习
looks like it's symbolic but I think
看起来它是象征性的，但我想
we'll do it with a connection system but
我们将使用连接系统来做到这一点
again I'm think the connection systems
再次， 我 认为连接系统
should develop a sense of hierarchy and
应该培养一种等级感和
not just be one big massive neural net
不仅仅是一个巨大的神经网络
so I understand how we want you know use
所以我理解我们希望你知道如何使用
the neocortex to extract useful stuff
新皮质提取有用的东西
and commercialize that but I'm wondering
并将其商业化，但我想知道
how you know our middle brain and organs
你怎么知道我们的 中脑 和 器官
that are below the neocortex will be
将在新皮层下方
useful for you know turn that into what
对你有用，知道把它变成 什么
you want to do something well the
你 想做点好事
cerebellum is an interesting case in
小脑是一个有趣的案例
point it actually has more neurons than
它实际上有 更多的神经元
the neocortex and it's used to
新皮质， 它已经习惯了
govern most of our behavior some things
管理我们大多数行为的一些事情
if you write a signature that's actually
如果你写一个实际的签名
controlled by the cerebellum so a simple
由小脑控制这么简单
sequence is stored in the cerebellum but
序列存储在小脑中但是
there's not many reasoning to it it's
它的推理并不多
basically a script and most of our
基本上是一个脚本 和我们的大多数
movement now has actually been migrated
现在运动实际上已经迁移了
from the center vellum to the neocortex
从中心牛皮纸到新皮质
cerebellum is still there some people
小脑还有 一些人
the entire cerebellum is destroyed
整个小脑都被摧毁了
through disease they still function
通过疾病他们仍然运作
fairly normally their movement might be
通常他们的运动可能是
a little erratic as our movements is
我们的动作有点不稳定
largely controlled by the neocortex but
很大程度上受 新皮层 控制 但是
some of the subtlety is a kind of
一些细微之处是一种
pre-programmed script and so they'll
预编程的 脚本，所以 他们会
look a little clumsy but they're
看起来有点笨拙，但 他们是
actually function okay a lot of other
其实 很多其他的 功能 还可以
areas of the brain control autonomic
大脑区域控制自主神经
functions like breathing and but our
功能，如呼吸， 但我们的
thinking really is is controlled by the
思想真的 是受到了控制
neocortex in terms of mastering
在掌握方面的新皮质
intelligence I think the neocortex is
智力我认为新皮层是
the brain region we want to study I'm
我们想研究的大脑区域
curious what you think might happen
好奇你认为可能会发生什么
after the singularity is reached in
在 达到奇点后
terms of this exponential growth of
这种指数增长 的条件
information yes do you think it will
信息是的，你 认为它会
continue or will there be a whole
继续或将有一个整体
paradigm shift what do you predict well
范式改变你对此有何预测
in the singularities near I talked about
在我所 谈到的奇点 附近
the atomic limits based on molecular
基于分子的原子极限
computing as we understand it and it can
计算，因为我们了解它，它可以
actually go well past 2045 and actually
居然顺利过去的2045和 实际
go to trillions of trillions of times
数以万亿计的数万亿次
greater computational capacity than we
比我们更大的计算能力
have today
今天有
so I don't see that's stopping anytime
所以我 不认为随时都会停止
soon and we'll go you know way beyond
很快， 我们会告诉你更远的方式
what we can imagine and it becomes an
我们可以想象的东西 ，它变成了一个
interesting discussion what the impact
有趣的讨论有什么影响
on human civilization will be so take it
关于人类文明将如此接受它
may be slightly more mundane issue that
可能是稍微平凡的问题
comes up as a kind of eliminates most
出来作为一种消除的最
jobs or
工作或
jobs a point I make is it's not the
工作的问题，我提出的是 它不是
first time in human history you've done
你已经完成了人类历史上的第一次
that how many jobs circa 1900 exist
大约1900年有多少工作存在
today and that was the feeling of the
今天那是感觉
Luddites which was an actual society
Luddites是一个真正的社会
that formed in 1800 the automation of
在1800年形成的自动化
the textile industry in England they
他们 在 英国的纺织业
looked at all these jobs going away and
看着所有这些离职的工作
felt that employment is going to be just
认为 就业 将是刚
limited to an elite indeed those jobs
确实限于精英那些工作
didn't go away but new jobs were created
没有消失，但创造了新的就业机会
so if I were oppression Futures to 1900
所以，如果我是压迫期货到1900年
I would say well 38% of you work on
我会说 38％的人都 在努力
farms and 25% work in factories it's 2/3
农场和25％在工厂工作，这是 2/3
of the working force but I predict by
工作力 ， 但我预测 由
2015 115 years from now it's going to be
从现在2015年115年这将 是
2% on farms and 9% factories and
2％ 的农场和9％的工厂和
everybody would go oh my God we're gonna
每个人都会去哦我的上帝我们会
be out of work and I said well don't
失业了，我说不好
worry for all these jobs we eliminate
担心我们消除的所有这些工作
through automation we're gonna invent
通过自动化，我们将发明
new jobs and say oh really what new jobs
新工作，并说哦，真的是什么新工作
and I'd say well I don't know we haven't
而且我会说好，我不 知道我们没有
invented them yet that's the political
发明了它们，但这是政治的
problem we could see jobs very clearly
问题我们 可以非常清楚地看到工作
going away fairly soon like driving a
很快就像开车一样离开了
car or truck and the new jobs haven't
汽车或 卡车和新的工作没有
been invented I mean just look at the
已经发明了我的意思只是看
last five or six years as many a lot of
过去的五年或六年 多了很多
the increase in employment has been
就业人数增加了
through mobile app related types of ways
通过移动应用程序相关的方式
of making money that just weren't
赚钱不是
contemplated even six years ago if I
如果我，甚至六 年前就考虑过
really prescient I would say well you're
真的有先见之明， 我会说你很好
gonna get jobs creating mobile apps and
要找到创造移动应用程序的工作
websites and doing data analytics and
网站和做数据分析和
self-driving cars cars what's a car and
自动驾驶汽车什么是汽车和汽车
nobody would have any idea what I'm
没有人会有 什么 想法 ， 我什么
talking about now the new job
现在谈论新工作
some people say yeah we created new jobs
有人说是的，我们创造了新的就业机会
but it's not as many actually we've gone
但实际上我们没有那么多
from 24 million jobs in nineteen hundred
从一千九 百年的 2400 万个工作岗位
242 million jobs today for 30 percent of
今天有2.42亿个工作岗位， 占30％
the population to forty five percent of
人口占百分之四十五
the population the new jobs pay eleven
人口新的工作岗位支付 11
times as much in constant dollars and
以不变美元和美元计算的时间
they're more interesting and as I talk
当我说话时，它们会更有趣
to people starting out their career now
人们现在开始了自己的职业生涯
they really want a career that gives
他们真的想要一个 给予 的职业
them some
他们一些
life definition and purpose and
生活的定义和 目的
gratification we're moving up Maslow's
满足我们正在向马斯洛迈进
hierarchy hundred years ago you were
一百年以前的等级你是
happy if you had a back-breaking job to
如果你有一个突破性的工作，我很高兴
put food on your family's table so and
把食物放在你家的餐桌上
we couldn't do these new jobs without
没有，我们不能做这些新工作
enhancing our intelligence so we've been
我们一直在增强智力
doing that well for most of the last 100
这样做， 适用于大多数的最后100
years through education we've expanded
通过教育， 我们已经扩大了多年
to K through 12 and constant dollars
从K到12和不变美元
tenfold
十倍
we've gone from 38,000 college students
我们已经从38,000名大学生中脱颖而出
in 1870 to 15 million today more
今天在1870年到15 多万
recently we have brain extenders and not
最近我们有脑扩展器而不是
yet connected directly in our brain but
但在我们的大脑直接相连，但
they're very close at hand when I was
我在他们的时候非常近在咫尺
here that my ta to take my bicycle
在这里， 我接受我的自行车
across campus to get to the computer and
穿过校园去电脑和
show an ID to get in the building now we
现在我们显示一个ID进入建筑物
carry them well you know in our in our
把它们带好，你知道我们在我们的
pockets and on our belts
口袋和腰带
they're going to go inside our bodies
他们会 进入我们的身体
and brains I think that's a notic really
和大脑我认为这是一个 真正 的 天才
important distinction but so we're
重要的区别， 但我们是
basically going to be continuing to
基本上将要 继续
enhance our capability through merging
通过合并来增强我们的能力
with AI and that's the I think ultimate
与AI ，这是我认为的 终极
answer to the kind of dystopian view we
回答我们的那种反乌托邦观点
see in futures movies where it's the AI
在期货电影中看到人工智能
versus a brave band of humans for
与一个勇敢的人类乐队
control of humanity we don't have one or
控制人性，我们没有一个或
two a eyes in the world today we have
我们今天拥有两只眼睛
several billion three billion
数十亿三十亿
smartphones and last count will be six
智能手机和最后的计数 将是 六
billion in just a couple of years
在短短 几年 内就达到 了十亿美元
according to the projections so we're
根据 预测 ，所以我们是
already deeply integrated with this and
已与此紧密集成 和
I think that's going to continue and
我认为这将继续下去
it's gonna continue to do things that
它会继续 做那些事情
you can't even imagine today just as we
就像我们一样，你甚至无法想象今天
are doing today things we couldn't
今天做的事我们做不到
imagine you know even twenty years ago
想象一下 ， 甚至 二十 年前 你也 知道
you showed many graphs that goes through
你发现 ，通过进入 许多图表
exponential growth but I haven't seen
指数增长，但我还没有看到
one that isn't so I would be very
一个不是 这样的我会 非常
interested in hearing you haven't seen
有兴趣听你还没见过
that what that is not exponential so
什么是 不 那么 指数
tell me about regions that you've
告诉我你所在的地区
investigated that have not seen
调查，没有看到
exponential growth and why do you think
指数增长，为什么你认为
that's the case well
情况就是这样
price performance and capacity of
价格表现和能力
information technology invariably
信息技术总是如此
follows a exponential when it impacts
当它影响时遵循指数
human society it can be linear so for
人类社会它可以是 线性 的
example the growth of democracy has been
例如民主的发展
linear but still pretty steady you can
线性，但仍然相当稳定，你可以
count the number of democracies on the
算上民主国家的数量
fingers of one hand a century ago two
一个世纪前 的一只 手的手指两个
centuries ago you can count the number
几个世纪前你可以算数
of democracies in the world on the
世界 上的 民主国家
fingers of one finger now there are
现在有 一根 手指的手指
dozens of them that this and it's become
他们中有数十人认为这就是它
kind of a consensus that that's how we
那是我们的共识
should be governed
应该受到 治理
so the and I attributed all this to the
所以我把这一切归功于
growth and information technology
增长和信息技术
communication in particular for
特别是为了沟通
progression of social cultural
社会文化的进步
institutions but information technology
机构， 但信息技术
because it ultimately depends on a
因为它最终取决于a
vanishingly small energy and material
消耗小的能量和材料
requirement grows exponentially and will
需求以指数方式增长并且将会增长
for a long time there's recently a
很长一段时间 有 一个 最近
criticism that well test scores have
对考试成绩有好的批评
it's actually a remarkably straight
它实际上非常直接
linear progression so humans think it's
线性进展让人们认为是这样
like twenty eight hundred and it just
就像二十八百只一样
sort passed out in 1997 with the blue
1997年 与 蓝色 一起 消失 了
and it's kept going and remarkably
并且它继续前进和 显着
straight and saying well this is linear
直，说得好，这是线性的
not exponential but the chess score is a
不是指数但国际象棋得分是一个
logarithmic measurement so it really is
对数测量所以它 确实是
exponential progression so if you're
指数级数， 所以如果 你是
lhasa furs like to think a lot about the
拉萨皮草喜欢思考很多
meaning of things especially in the 20th
事物的意义尤其在 20世纪
century so for instance Martin Heidegger
世纪 ，比如 Martin Heidegger
gave a couple of speeches and lectures
发表了几个演讲和讲座
on the relationship of human society to
对人类社会的关系
technology and he particularly
技术，他特别
distinguished between the mode of
模式之间可分辨
thinking which is calculating thinking
思考哪个 是计算思维
and a mode of thinking which is
以及一种思维方式
reflective thinking or meditative
反思思维或冥想
thinking and he posed this question what
思考，他提出了这个问题
is the the meaning and purpose of
是的意义和 目的
technological development and he
技术发展和他
couldn't find an answer he he
他找不到答案
recommended to remain open to what he
建议对他保持开放态度
called and he called this an openness to
他称这是开放的
the mystery I wonder whether you have
这个谜 我不知道 你有没有
any thoughts on this is there is there a
对此 有 任何想法 是有一个
meaning of purpose to technological
技术 目的的意义
equipment and and is there a way for a
设备 ，是有 一个 办法
human success access that meaning well
人类成功获取意义很好
we started using technology to shore up
我们开始使用技术来支撑
weaknesses and our own capabilities so
弱点和我们自己的能力所以
physically I mean who here could build
身体上我的意思是谁可以建立
this building so we've leveraged the
这座建筑让我们充分利用了
power of our muscles with machines
我们用机器锻炼肌肉的力量
and we're in fact very bad at doing
事实上 ，我们做得 非常糟糕
things that you know the simplest
你知道最简单的事情
computers can do like factor numbers or
计算机可以像因素数字或
even just multiply two eight digit
即使只是乘以 两个八位数
numbers computers can do that trivially
数字计算机可以做到这一点
we can't do it so we originally started
我们不能这样做，所以我们最初开始
using computers to make up for that
用计算机来 弥补 这一点
weakness I think the essence of what
弱点我认为 是什么 的本质
I've been writing about is to master the
我一直在写的是掌握 了
unique strengths of humanity creating
人类创造的独特优势
loving expressions in poetry and music
在诗歌和音乐中表达爱意
and the kinds of things we associate
以及我们 联想 到的 事物
with the better qualities of humanity
具有更好的人性素质
with machines that's the to promise of
机器是 承诺的
AI that we're not there yet but we're
AI，我们还没有， 但我们是
making pretty stunning progress just in
正在取得令人惊叹的 进步
the last year there's so many milestones
去年有很多里程碑
that are really significant including in
这是真正显著包括
language and but I think of technology
语言，但我想到的是技术
as an expression of humanity it's part
作为人性的表达，它是其中的一部分
of who we are and the human species is
我们 是 谁 ，人类是 谁
already a biological technological
已经是生物技术
civilization and it's part of who we are
文明，它是我们的一部分
an AI is it's part of humans so AI is
人工智能是人类的一部分 所以人工智能是
human and it's it's part of the
人类， 这是它的一部分
technological expression of humanity and
人性与科学的技术表达
we use technology to extend our reach
我们使用技术扩展我们的业务范围
you know I couldn't reach that fruit at
你知道我无法达到 那个水果
that higher branch a thousand years ago
一千年前的那个更高的分支
so we invented a tool to extend our
所以我们发明了一种扩展我们的工具
physical reach we now extend our mental
身体到达我们现在扩展我们的心理
reach we can access all of human
达到我们可以访问所有 人类
knowledge with a few keystrokes and
知识 与几个键击和
we're going to make ourselves literally
我们要从字面上做出自己
smarter by merging with AI hi
通过 与AI hi合并更聪明
first of all honor to hear you speak
首先 荣幸地听到你说话
here so I first read The Singularity is
所以我首先阅读 The Singularity
near nine years ago or so and it changed
大约九 年前左右，它改变了
the way I thought entirely but something
我完全想到的方式，但有些东西
I think it caused me to over steeply
我认为这让我过于陡峭
discount was tail risk in geopolitics in
折扣是地缘政治的 尾部风险
systems that span the entire globe and
跨越 全球的系统
my concern is that there are there is
我担心的是有
obviously the possibility of tail risk
显然有尾部风险的可能性
existential level events swamp in all of
存在水平事件沼泽所有
these trends that are otherwise war
这些趋势本来就是战争
proof climate proof you name it so my
证明气候证明你这么说我的名字
question for you is what steps do you
你的问题是你的步骤
think we can take in designing
我认为我们可以参与设计
engineered systems in designing social
设计社会系统的工程系统
and economic institutions to kind of
和经济制度有关
minimize our exposure to these tail
尽量减少我们接触 这些尾巴
risks and and and survive to make it to
风险和和和生存，使其向
UM you know a beautiful mind filled
UM你知道一个美丽的 心灵充满
future yeah well the world was first
未来耶以及 世界首次
introduced to a human-made
介绍给人造
existential risk when I was in
当我进入时存在风险
elementary school we would have these
小学， 我们会有这些
civil defense drills to get under our
民防演习深入到我们的手中
desk and put our hands behind our head
桌子 ，把我们的手 放在头后
to protect this from a thermonuclear war
为了 保护这从一个热核战争
and it worked we made it through but
它起作用我们完成了 但是
that was really the first introduction
这真的是 第一次介绍
to an existential risk and those weapons
存在风险和那些 武器
are still there by the way and they're
顺便说一句， 他们 还在那里
still on a hair-trigger and they don't
仍然在触发 ，他们没有
get that much attention there's been a
得到那么 多的关注 有一个
lot of discussion much of which I've
我讨论了很多
been in the forefront of initiating the
一直站在 发起的 最前沿
existential risks of what sometimes
有时存在的风险
referred to as GN rg4 genetics which is
被称为GN rg4遗传学
biotechnology and for nanotechnology and
生物技术和纳米技术和
gray goo robotics which is a
灰色粘性机器人这是一个
and I've been accused of being an
而且我被指责为一个人
optimist I think you have to be an
乐观主义者我认为你必须是一个
optimist to be an entrepreneur if you
乐观主义者，如果你是一个企业家
knew all the problems you were going to
知道你要去的所有问题
encounter you'd never start any project
遇到你永远不会开始任何项目
but I've written a lot about the
但我写了很多关于
downsides I remain optimistic there are
缺点我仍然乐观
specific paradigms and not foolproof
具体范式并非万无一失
that we can follow to keep these
我们可以遵循以保持这些
technologies safe so for example over 40
技术安全，例如 超过 40
years ago some visionaries recognized
几年前， 一些有远见的人认可
the revolutionary potential both for
两者的革命潜力
promise and peril of biotechnology
生物技术的承诺和危险
neither the promise no peril was
承诺没有 危险
feasible 40 years ago but they had a
40年前 可行， 但他们有一个
conference at the Asilomar conference
在Asilomar会议上召开会议
center in California and to develop both
加利福尼亚州的中心， 并发展两者
professional ethics and strategies to
职业道德和战略
keep biotechnology safe and they've been
保持生物技术的安全，他们一直都是
known as the Asilomar guidelines they've
被称为 他们已经在阿西洛马指南
been refined through successive sell
通过连续出售得到了提炼
more conferences much of that's baked
更多会议的大部分都是烘焙过的
into law and it in my opinion it's
成为法律，在我看来它是
worked quite well we're now as I
工作得很好我们现在就像 我一样
mentioned getting profound benefit it's
提到了它的深刻利益
a trickle today it'll be a flood over
今天涓涓细流，这将是洪水泛滥
the next decade and the number of people
未来十年和人数
who have been harmed either through
谁受伤了
intentional or accidental abuse of
故意或意外滥用
biotechnology so far zero actually I
生物技术到目前为止我实际上是零
take that back there was one boy who
拿回那里有一个男孩
died in gene therapy trials but 12 years
死于基因治疗试验但 12 年
ago and there's congressional hearings
之前还有国会听证会
and they cancelled all research for gene
他们 取消了所有基因研究
therapy for a number of years you could
你可以 治疗 多年
do an interesting master's thesis and
做一个有趣的硕士论文 和
demonstrate that you know 300,000 people
证明你知道 300,000人
died as a result of that delay but you
因为 那次延迟 而死了 ，但是你
can't name them they can't go on CNN so
不能说出他们不能去CNN 所以
we don't know who they are but it has to
我们不知道他们是谁，但必须这样做
do with the balancing of risk but in
做风险 的平衡 ，但在
large measure virtually no one has been
几乎没有人参与其中
hurt by biotechnology now that doesn't
现在生物技术伤害 是 不
mean you can cross on our front list
意思是你可以 在我们的前列表上 交叉
okay we took care of that one because
好吧，我们 照顾那个， 因为
the technology keeps getting more
该 技术不断得到更多的
sophisticated and Christopher's great
老练而且克里斯托弗 很棒
opportunity there's hundreds of trials
机会有数百次试验
of Christopher's technologies overcome
克里斯托弗的技术克服了
disease but it could be abused you can
疾病但 你可以滥用 它
describe scenarios so we have to keep
描述场景所以我们必须保持
reinventing it January we had our first
重塑它1月我们有了 第一个
Asilomar conference on AI ethics and so
关于人工智能道路的Asilomar会议等
I think this is a good paradigm it's not
我认为这是一个很好的范例，但事实并非如此
foolproof I think the best way we can
万无一失我认为我们能做到最好
assure a democratic future that includes
确保包括的民主未来
our ideas of Liberty is to practice that
我们对自由的想法就是实践
in the world today because the future
在今天的世界因为未来
world of the singularity which is a
奇点世界是一个
merger of biological non-biological
生物 非生物的合并
intelligence it's not going to come from
情报它不会来自
Mars I mean it's going to emerge from
火星 我的意思是它会 从 出现
our society today so if we practice
今天我们的社会， 所以如果我们练习
these ideals today it's going to have a
今天这些理想 会有一个
higher chance of us practicing them as
我们练习它们的 机会更高
we get more enhanced with technology if
我们得到更多的增强， 如果 技术
that doesn't sound like a foolproof
这听起来不像一个 万无一失
solution it isn't but I think that's the
解决方案不是， 但我认为是
best approach in terms of technological
技术方面的最佳方法
solutions
解决方案
I mean AI is the most daunting you can
我的意思是人工智能是 最令人生畏的
imagine there are technical solutions to
想象有技术解决方案
biotechnology and nanotechnology there's
那里有生物技术和纳米技术
really no subroutine you can put in your
真的没有你可以放入你的子程序
AI software there will assure that it
AI软件会保证 它
remains safe intelligence it's
它仍然是安全的情报
inherently not controllable
本质上不可控制
there's some AI that's much smarter than
有一些人工智能 比智能手机要聪明 得多
you that's out for your destruction the
你这是从你的毁灭
best way to deal with that is not to get
解决这个问题的最佳方法是不要
in that situation in the first place if
在那种情况下，如果
if you are in that situation and find
如果你在那种情况下找到
some AI that will be on your side but
一些AI会在你身边，但是
basically it's going to eyeb Aleve
基本上它会关注 Aleve
we have been headed through technology
我们一直在技​​术领域
to event to a better reality look around
以更好的现实环顾 四周
the world and people really think things
世界和人们真的在想事
are getting worse and I think that's
日益严重， 我认为这是
because our information about what's
因为我们的信息是关于 什么的
wrong with the world is getting
错误的世界正 变得越来越
exponentially better I say oh this is
指数好我说哦，这是
the most peaceful time on you in history
历史 上 最 和平的时光
if you say what are you crazy didn't you
如果你说 你疯了 什么 不是你
hear about the event yesterday and last
昨天 和 最后一次 听到这个事件
week and well a hundred years ago there
一周和一百年前那里
could be a battle that wiped out the
可能是一场彻底消灭的战斗
next village in you wouldn't even hear
在你的下一个村庄 甚至都 听不到
about it for months
关于它几个月
of all these graphs on education and
所有这些关于教育和教育的图表
literacy has gone from like 10% to 90%
识字率从10％上升到 90％
over a century and health wealth
一个多世纪以来的 健康财富
poverty's declined 95% in Asia over the
贫困在 亚洲 比 下降 95％
last 25 years document about the World
关于 世界的 最近25年的 文件
Bank all these trends are very smoothly
银行所有这些趋势 都 非常顺利
getting better and everybody thinks
越来越好，每个人都在想
things are getting worse but but but
事情变得越来越糟，但是但是
you're right like on violence that curve
你是对的，就像暴力曲线一样
could be quite disrupted there's an
可能会被打乱， 有一个
existential event as I say I'm
存在的事件，就像我说的那样
optimistic but I think that is something
乐观， 但我认为这是事情
if we need to deal with that a lot of it
如果我们需要处理与 它 的很多
is not technological it's dealing with
是不是技术它在处理
our social cultural institutions so you
我们的社会文化机构让你如此
mentioned also exponential growth of
提到也是指数增长
software and IDs I guess related to
我想与之相关的软件和ID
software so one of the reasons for which
软件这样的 原因， 其中 之一
you said that all that information
你说所有的信息
technology costs this exponential is
这种 指数的 技术成本 是
because of fundamental properties of
因为基本属性
matter and energy but in the case of
物质和能量，但在情况下
ideas why would it have to be
想法为什么会这样
exponential well a lot of ideas produce
指数很好的想法产生了很多
exponential gains they don't increase
它们不会增加指数增益
performance linearly there's actually
实际上是线性的
study during the Obama administration by
奥巴马政府期间的研究
his scientific advisory board on
他的科学顾问 委员会
assessing this question how much gains
评估这个问题有多大收益
on 23 classical engineering problems
关于23个经典工程问题
were gained through hardware
是通过硬件获得的
improvements over the last decade and
过去十年的改进和
software improvements and there's about
软件改进和那里有关于
a thousand to one improvement it's about
一千一改进 这是关于
doubling every year from Hardware there
每年从硬件那里翻倍
was an averages of like twenty six
平均有二十六个
thousand to one through softer
通过更柔软的一千比一
improvements algorithmic improvements so
改进算法的改进， 所以
we do see both and apparently if you
如果你，我们确实看到了两者
come up with in advance its it doubles
事先提出它的双打
the performance or multiplies it by ten
表现或乘以 十
we see basically exponential growth from
我们看到基本上呈指数增长
each innovation
每一项创新
so and we certainly see that in deep
所以，我们肯定会看到， 在深
learning the architectures are getting
学习 架构越来越好
better
更好
while we also have more data and more
而我们也有更多的数据
computation and more memory to throw in
计算和更多的内存投入
these at these algorithms
这些算法就是这些
thank you for being
谢谢你的存在